<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Dev@Cloudburo</title>
  <subtitle>Developer Blog of Cloudburo</subtitle>
  <id>http://dev.cloudburo.net</id>
  <link href="http://dev.cloudburo.net"/>
  <link href="http://dev.cloudburo.net/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-01-31T07:04:36Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Felix Küstahler</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Google Ventures releases new DIY guide to help startups</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/01/31/google-ventures-releases-new-diy-guide-to-help-startups.html"/>
    <id>http://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/01/31/google-ventures-releases-new-diy-guide-to-help-startups.html</id>
    <published>2015-01-31T07:04:36Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-06T23:09:10+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;dummy&gt;      Interesting new DIY Guide by Google, which helps startups to design better products.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Google’s venture capital arm released a new do-it-yourself guide for startups looking to run a &amp;quot;design sprint&amp;quot; — Google Ventures’ name for its well-known five-day prototyping process.
    Google Ventures has long preached the concept and has publicly detailed its various stages, from idea development and prototyping to user testing. With today’s release, however, the design sprint guide gets a lot more formal, and sets the stage for Google Ventures’ plan to publish its techniques in book form
    &lt;a href="http://www.gv.com/sprint/"&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Future Of Work</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://dev.cloudburo.net/2014/11/10/the-future-of-work.html"/>
    <id>http://dev.cloudburo.net/2014/11/10/the-future-of-work.html</id>
    <published>2014-11-10T11:48:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-06T15:44:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An nice food for tought presentation which outlines the importance of leveraging internal and external talents in future working models, which are increasingly digital.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Companies don&amp;#39;t necessarily deal in things, but they deal in knowledge, worthwile read.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src="http://www.slideshare.net/slideshow/embed_code/27110077?rel=0" width="512" height="421" frameborder="0" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" style="border:1px solid #CCC;border-width:1px 1px 0;margin-bottom:5px" allowfullscreen&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt; &lt;div style="margin-bottom:5px"&gt; &lt;strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.slideshare.net/Achievers/the-future-of-work-27110077" title="The Future of Work" target="_blank"&gt;The Future of Work&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.slideshare.net/Achievers" target="_blank"&gt;Achievers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>User, Customer, Partner some thoughts about terminology in banking</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://dev.cloudburo.net/2014/10/21/user-customer-partner.html"/>
    <id>http://dev.cloudburo.net/2014/10/21/user-customer-partner.html</id>
    <published>2014-10-21T15:45:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-06T15:44:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There is an entertaining debate kicked off by @Jack &amp;quot;Jack Dorsey&amp;quot; (Twitter  and Square founder) on a business concept term level, which resulted in a follow up by @davewiner &amp;quot;Dave Winer&amp;quot;&amp;quot; (pioneered the development of weblogs, syndication (RSS), podcasting and others). &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;!--more--&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;In short the social web icon Jack Dorsey  was challenging in his tumblr blog the core concept &lt;em&gt;user&lt;/em&gt;, as nicely formulated by Dave&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Why do we use that awful U-word to describe our users&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;According to Jack the term &lt;em&gt;user&lt;/em&gt; is too passive and abstract for describing the clientele of Square&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The entire technology industry uses the word “user” to describe its customers. While it might be convenient, “users” is a rather passive and abstract word. No one wants to be thought of as a “user” (or “consumer” for that matter). I certainly don’t. And I wouldn’t consider my mom a “user” either, she’s my mom. The word “user” abstracts the actual individual. This may seem like a small and insignificant detail that doesn’t matter, but the vernacular and words we use here at Square set a very strong and subtle tone for everything we do. So let’s now part ways with our industry and rethink this.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;(via &lt;a href="http://jacks.tumblr.com/post/33785796042/lets-reconsider-our-users"&gt;Let&amp;#39;s reconsider our &amp;quot;users&amp;quot; - Jack&amp;#39;s&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;So he asks for a mind shift in his company and to switch to the term &lt;em&gt;customer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At Square we’re removing the term “users” from our vocabulary, replacing it with “customers”, and the more specific “buyers”, and “sellers.” The word customer, given its history, immediately sets a high bar on the level of service we must provide, or risk losing their attention or business. Below is a letter I sent the team after that Board meeting explaining why. It’s a start (we’re not done yet).&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;#39;s a statement, which got challenged by Dave. &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s hard to even formulate the question without sounding stupid. And every time the discussion comes up, it lasts a while before everyone gives up because there really aren&amp;#39;t any better words, and this is the word everyone uses so what are you going to do.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;which continues&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Hey I called my second company UserLand Software, because I wanted to be clear who we were focused on. The idea was we would make a wonderful playground that we, as users, would love to er ahem -- use. And we&amp;#39;d make it easy enough to develop apps inside the land that developers and users would find they became the same people. Software made by users for users. This was a good idea, I felt.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;(via &lt;a href="http://threads2.scripting.com/2012/october/aboutCallingUsersUsers#daveWiner"&gt;Thread: Let&amp;#39;s call them users&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Well to be honest both side have their points and the debate could go on definitely for some time. It remembers me at my endless discussions at UBS  when we were ( well we are still aligning it) working out a global business concept model in the area of static client data and aligning the different views of the topic by regional wealth management units of Switzerland, APAC, Americas as well as the diametral view of the global acting investment bank unit. &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Let me give you an overview how a classic financial institution is modeling this business concept (which yet will give you another view on these concepts)&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;First of all I take here the radical target view that the business model of a classic bank at the end isn&amp;#39;t really different than that of any new social stylish company.  Currently there is a big shift in todays enterprises from a push model to a pull one which holds true for banks as well (if the current big player in banking will be enough fast to convert to this new model is questionable and time will show us who will survive) . Refer to my earlier  &lt;a href="http://cloudburo.github.com/blog/2012/10/16/the-big-shift/"&gt;Blog entry&lt;/a&gt;, where I describe this trend in more detail (based on the research paper by John Hagel) &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Things are different in a service-oriented company. The sale of the product is merely the inauguration of the customer relationship, with many subsequent interactions to follow. And the service-oriented company may offer to transfer the product to the customer in return for a stream of payments, instead of one initial sum. The company and customer remain engaged throughout the stream of payments.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;So a bank is a classical service oriented company which is approaching customers over various channels in order to sell services which are packaged into banking products. Not the selling of the product is in the center but to establish a long lasting relationship. &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;First of all we start with the concept  &lt;strong&gt;Party&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Party&lt;/strong&gt;  is a person or group of persons that compose a single entity which can be identified as one for the purposes of the law. &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;So any person with which a bank deals and interacts is a &lt;strong&gt;Party&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;The bank itself will be named in this context the &lt;strong&gt;Legal Entity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Legal Entity&lt;/strong&gt; is an association, corporation, partnership, proprietorship, trust, or individual that has legal standing in the eyes of law. A legal entity has legal capacity to enter into agreements or contracts, assume obligations, incur and pay debts, sue and be sued in its own right, and to be held responsible for its actions.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;A legal entity is a key concept taken into consideration that a multinational bank consists of a tremendous amount of independent legal entities (within a country itself as well as globally), which must be correctly identified in the business modeling. As the definition is outlining, legal entity would also be the correct concept in a micro business with one individual. From a business purpose he has the legal capacity to open up a startup business (but a minor wouldn&amp;#39;t have this capacity on its own).&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;From a birds eye view a bank or enterprise is made up of a collection of &lt;strong&gt;Legal Entities&lt;/strong&gt; which are in &lt;strong&gt;Business Relationships&lt;/strong&gt; with  &lt;strong&gt;Parties&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Business Relationship&lt;/strong&gt; is expressing the relationship between a &lt;strong&gt;Party&lt;/strong&gt; and a &lt;strong&gt;Legal Entity&lt;/strong&gt; which are doing any kind of business.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;On that level a party can be anything, it could be&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;real estate company&lt;/em&gt; which is renting out office space to the bank&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;third party financial company&lt;/em&gt; which issues some instruments packaged into a banking product and sold to its customers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The &lt;em&gt;bank customer&lt;/em&gt; which is opening up a banking account and purchases some services&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;But also the &lt;em&gt;cleaning company&lt;/em&gt; which takes care that the office got cleaned on a periodical base.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s clear that the concept of  &lt;strong&gt;Party&lt;/strong&gt; is too coarse grain to express the customer which is buying products from us and which is highly valuable  (it&amp;#39;s on the same level as the concept user used in the new social business).&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;What we introduced is the concept of &lt;strong&gt;Partner&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Partner&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;strong&gt;Party&lt;/strong&gt; which is any kind of relationship with a &lt;strong&gt;Legal Entity&lt;/strong&gt; concerning our service- or product offering.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;So a &lt;strong&gt;Partner&lt;/strong&gt; is really a &lt;strong&gt;Party&lt;/strong&gt; which is important for our core business and therefore we should treat and act with him as any of persons with whom were in any kind of &lt;strong&gt;Partnership&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Partnership&lt;/strong&gt; is an arrangement where parties agree to cooperate to advance their mutual interests.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Advance their mutual interests&lt;/em&gt; (that one of the bank and the one of the customer) should be the ultimate target to achieve, which will  result in a hopefully long lasting relationship and finally generate earnings for both sides.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;We differentiate the following Partners.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Partner&lt;/strong&gt; which expresses interest to enter into a &lt;strong&gt;Banking Relationship&lt;/strong&gt; with one &lt;strong&gt;Legal Entity&lt;/strong&gt; in order to be advised and/or to buy products of the bank (a so called &lt;strong&gt;Prospect&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Partner&lt;/strong&gt; which is in a &lt;strong&gt;Banking Relationship&lt;/strong&gt; and which is advised and/or bought banking products. At the end this the so-called &lt;strong&gt;Customer&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Partner&lt;/strong&gt; which is in a relationship with another &lt;strong&gt;Partner&lt;/strong&gt; which has a &lt;strong&gt;Banking Relationship&lt;/strong&gt; with the bank. This  &lt;strong&gt;Partner to Partner Relationship&lt;/strong&gt; is another important concept which is used to express relationships like &lt;strong&gt;Power of Attorney&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Beneficial Owner&lt;/strong&gt; etc. &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Concepts" src="images/coreconcepts.png" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;In order to complete the picture we have to define the incarnation  of a Banking Relationship more precisely.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A &lt;strong&gt;Banking Relationship&lt;/strong&gt; between a &lt;strong&gt;Partner&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Legal Entity&lt;/strong&gt; will be created as soon as the &lt;strong&gt;Partner&lt;/strong&gt; will sign a &lt;strong&gt;Banking Agreement&lt;/strong&gt; (or more) in order to benefit and purchase services by the bank. &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;By signing a &lt;strong&gt;Banking Agreement&lt;/strong&gt; an on-boarding will take place, which results in diligence verification checks of the Partner. The importance and complexity of such &amp;quot;Know Your Customers&amp;quot; (KYC) checks  is growing rapidly in relation with the number of new legal and regulatory intoruced in the financial market. This on-boarding will result in some kind of signed physical or electronically signed form(s) which are an integral part of the newly created &lt;strong&gt;Banking Relationship&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Having reached this point the bank is looking forward for a fruitful and long lasting partnership with its customer.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;This concludes this blog entry, how are you modelling the customer, user or partner in your conceptual models? Any comments appreciated.&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Big Shift</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://dev.cloudburo.net/2014/10/19/the-big-shift.html"/>
    <id>http://dev.cloudburo.net/2014/10/19/the-big-shift.html</id>
    <published>2014-10-19T23:35:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-06T15:44:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I came recently across the Shift Index study and the discussion resulted out of this research work done by consultancy company Deloitte.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Goal of the study is to measure the forces of the long term changes that impact our economic. It’s an excellent and well written inspiring research study which helps you to understand the transformation process of our current business world.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;!--more--&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Shift Index tracks 25 metrics in nine categories across three sets of main indicators: Foundations, which set the stage for major change; Flows of resources, such as knowledge, which allow businesses to enhance productivity; and Impacts, which help gauge progress at an economy-wide level. Together these indicators represent phases of transformation in the Big Shift taking place in the global business environment.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://blogs.hbr.org/bigshift/2009/06/measuring-the-big-shift.html"&gt;via Measuring The Big Shift -  - John Hagel III and John Seely Brown - Harvard Business Review&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Obviously a major trend is the conversion from a push model (product focused business)  to a pull model (service oriented business). The inherent differences are nicely outlined in the report as follows&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A product conception for revenues means that the big money comes from The Sale, when the customer buys the product. A large lump sum of money is paid at that point, and then the customer uses that product as he or she wishes. A product-focused business spends relatively little time or money with the customer after that, until the time comes for the next sale. This is the Push approach to business.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Things are different in a service-oriented company. The sale of the product is merely the inauguration of the customer relationship, with many subsequent interactions to follow. And the service-oriented company may offer to transfer the product to the customer in return for a stream of payments, instead of one initial sum. The company and customer remain engaged throughout the stream of payments&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;So the key point here is constant engagement with the customer, who has the possibility to pull services with minimal upfront investment and check their quality in a fully operational mode. Any overselling done beforehand by the company will be uncovered quickly and result in an exit of the customer.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In this way, a fixed cost is converted to a variable cost.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;A key indicator the reports is measuring in order identify the economy shift is the return on assets (ROA). It shows the persistent decline in firm performance, manifested in declining asset profitability. It’s a downward trend due to the deterioration of fundamental firm performance. In order to shift away from this downward trend the economy will has to absorb three wave of changes and innovations.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The first, the &lt;strong&gt;Foundation&lt;/strong&gt; wave, involves changes to the fundamentals of our business landscape catalyzed by the emergence and spread of digital technology infrastructure and reinforced by long-term public policy shifts toward economic liberalization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The second, the &lt;strong&gt;Flow&lt;/strong&gt; wave, focuses on the key drivers of performance in a world increasingly shaped by digital infrastructure. This second wave looks at the flows of knowledge, capital, and talent enabled by the foundational advances, as well as the amplifiers of these flows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The third, the &lt;strong&gt;Impact&lt;/strong&gt; wave, centers on the consequences of the Big Shift. Given the time it will take for the first two waves to play out and manifest themselves, this third wave provides an even greater lagging indicator. While current trends in firm performance indicate sustained deterioration, we expect, over time, that performance will improve as firms begin to figure out how to participate in and harness knowledge flows. Doing so will require significant institutional innovations, not just changes in practices, resulting in value creation through increasing returns performance improvement.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;It’s a move from scalable efficiency to scalable as firms used digital infrastructure to create environments where performance improvement accelerates as more participants join.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;A nice follow up on the base of the Shift Index can be found in the confusedofcalcutta blog which brings the waves into the context of the Social enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://confusedofcalcutta.com/2012/05/30/thinking-about-the-big-shift-and-the-social-enterprise/"&gt;Thinking about the Big Shift and the Social Enterprise – confused of calcutta&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Concept&lt;/strong&gt; of the Social Enterprise is underpinned by the cloud: a public digital infrastructure based on open standards, scalable and elastic. In effect, it represents the Foundation “wave” of the Big Shift.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Core&lt;/strong&gt; of the Social Enterprise is connectivity, bringing about collaboration and co-creation; customers, staff, partners and products are all connected, using common “language”, facilitating the transformation of the organization from experience-based to learning-based, from stocks-based to flows-based. In effect, this represents the Flows “wave” of the Big Shift.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Construct&lt;/strong&gt; of the Social Enterprise is institutional innovation: innovation in engagement, in sales, in marketing, in service, in product engineering and design. The scalability and flexibility of the infrastructure, combined with the ease of identification and access to the right resources at the right time, allow the enterprise to find areas of high growth potential simply, effectively and affordably.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Overall very profound and mind opening reading about the current economic transformation process.&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Reactive Manifesto</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://dev.cloudburo.net/2014/07/27/the-reactive-manifesto.html"/>
    <id>http://dev.cloudburo.net/2014/07/27/the-reactive-manifesto.html</id>
    <published>2014-07-27T13:37:00Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-06T15:44:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Stumbled recently over &lt;strong&gt;The Reactive Manifesto&lt;/strong&gt; which nicely describes the principles of the new application architecture style, which emerged in the last years, due to the exponential growth of mobile internet usage.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;… a new architecture has evolved to let developers conceptualize and build applications that satisfy today’s demands. We call these Reactive Applications. This architecture allows developers to build systems that are event-driven, scalable, resilient and interactive: delivering highly interactive user experiences with a real-time feel, backed by a scalable and resilient application stack, ready to be deployed on multicore and cloud computing architectures. The Reactive Manifesto describes these critical traits which are needed for going reactive. &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;The Manifesto is maintained and managed in github and can be found &lt;a href="http://www.reactivemanifesto.org/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Fullstack Developer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://dev.cloudburo.net/2014/04/16/fullstack-developer.html"/>
    <id>http://dev.cloudburo.net/2014/04/16/fullstack-developer.html</id>
    <published>2014-04-16T18:20:31Z</published>
    <updated>2015-03-06T15:44:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;An &lt;a href="http://http//www.huffingtonpost.com/mike-loukides/fullstack-developer-is-a-_b_5134310.html"&gt;interesting article&lt;/a&gt; in Huffington Post calls for action by developers to broaden their range, in order to get a &amp;quot;Full Stack Developer&amp;quot;. The article provides an overview and various definitions of this new tech role and comes to the conclusion: &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What&amp;#39;s really needed isn&amp;#39;t someone who can replace all the specializations that the silos represented, but someone who can work across those specializations, someone who can work productively with people on other parts of the team.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Exposing yourself to new ideas and try to get an understanding of the whole stack is key&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Full-stack development is about exposing yourself to a broad range of ideas. This is a theme we&amp;#39;ll see repeatedly in the coming years. Being a full-stack developer isn&amp;#39;t about jumping
    immediately from working on the Hadoop cluster to the Java middleware to the JavaScript that runs in the browser. Specialization exists for a reason. But developers who understand the whole stack are going to build better applications.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;A strategy which personally drives my daily work, as well as my spare time development work. &lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;... being a full-stack developer is a tall order, but it&amp;#39;s as much aspirational as anything else. &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
