<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>dev@cloudburo</title>
  <subtitle>Cloudburo Developer Blog</subtitle>
  <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net/</id>
  <link href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/"/>
  <link href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2015-09-30T06:31:36Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Felix Kuestahler</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Micro Business Quick Tips #3: Visualizing your Business Model with Canvas</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/09/30/micro-business-quick-tips-3-visualizing-your-business-model-with-canvas.html"/>
    <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/09/30/micro-business-quick-tips-3-visualizing-your-business-model-with-canvas.html</id>
    <published>2015-09-30T06:31:36Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-30T06:31:36+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
        For young startup founders having a bright idea it’s important that they understand and define the underlying Business Model which drives their Product or Service offering. A Business- or Operating model may be abstract or difficult to grasp in the beginning, especially for unexperienced entrepreneurs which are bootstrapping their first company. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Luckily the Swiss guy 
       &lt;a href="http://alexosterwalder.com/"&gt;Alex Osterwalder&lt;/a&gt; invented the 
       &lt;a href="http://businessmodelgeneration.com/canvas/bmc"&gt;Business Model Canvas&lt;/a&gt; approach which is easy to use strategic management and entrepreneurial tool. It condenses your business model visually onto one page and allows you to describe, design, challenge, invent and pivot your business model. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Assembling the startup team (get all the various disciplines together) around a visual business model diagram on a flip-board and interactively discuss and shape out the 9 basic building blocks of your business model is an excellent and agile way to get clarity about your initial company setup. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        The following video gives a short two minute intro to the 9 building blocks of the Business Model Canvas approach.&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;div class="responsive-video"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QoAOzMTLP5s?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Well potentially still a little bit abstract, luckily there are some good examples which will map the canvas approach to some real life examples. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Strategyzer - the company co-founded by Alex Osterwalder - released a set of mini video tutorials (six in total), which describes the approach in an animated series „ 
       &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLBh9h0LWoawphbpUvC1DofjagNqG1Qdf3"&gt;From Idea to Business&lt;/a&gt;“. It’s worth to spend around 15 minutes to get a better understanding of the approach. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Episode 2 of series „Visualizing Your Business Model“ is introducing the concept via the  company „Cheap Flights“ and explains the 9 ingredients of the approach: 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;ul&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Value Proposition&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Customer Segments&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Customer Relationships&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Channels&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Revenue Streams&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Key Activities&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Key Resources&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Key Partnerships&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Cost Structures&lt;/li&gt; 
      &lt;/ul&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;div class="responsive-video"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/wlKP-BaC0jA?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        There is always the danger to fall in love with your first „cool“ idea and not spend time in prototype multiple business model options. Episode 3 is introducing you to this concept. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;div class="responsive-video"&gt;&lt;iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/iA5MVUNkSkM?rel=0" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Needless to say that the approach is backed by a very 
       &lt;a href="http://businessmodelgeneration.com/book"&gt;nice „visual“ book&lt;/a&gt;, which is a source of inspirations for young entrepreneurs. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Additional Links: 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;ul&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Interested in a German introduction ? Head over to startwerk.de which gives you an &lt;a href="http://www.startplatz.de/startup-wiki/business-model-canvas/"&gt;introduction of the nine building blocks&lt;/a&gt; in German.&lt;/li&gt; 
      &lt;/ul&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Micro Business Quick Tips #3: Rechtssicherheit bei der Eröffnung eines Onlineshops in der Schweiz</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/09/29/micro-business-quick-tips-3-rechtssicherheit-bei-der-eroffnung-eines-onlineshops.html"/>
    <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/09/29/micro-business-quick-tips-3-rechtssicherheit-bei-der-eroffnung-eines-onlineshops.html</id>
    <published>2015-09-29T10:32:56Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-29T22:48:11+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
        Der Betrieb eines Onlineshops oder einer E-Commerce Lösung ist für ein Startup oft ein wichtiger Verkaufskanal und integraler Bestandteil des entsprechenden Businessmodells.&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Via dem Onlineshop wird eine elektronischer Verkaufsprozess zwischen dem Kunden und dem Startup abgewickelt, welcher - wie jeder andere Verkauf in einem normalen Laden - rechtlichen Bestimmungen des entsprechenden Landes unterliegt. Punkte, welche in dem gedrängten Zeitrahmen eines Startup Launch oft untergehen und den Internet Absatzkanal auf ein wackliges, rechtliches Fundament stellen. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Startwerk.ch hat hierzu einen sehr hilfreiche 
       &lt;a href="http://www.startwerk.ch/2014/10/10/startups-rechtssicherheit-bei-der-eroeffnung-eines-onlineshops/"&gt;Anleitung&lt;/a&gt; erstellt, welche die verschieden rechtliche Aspekte des Schweizer Gesetzgebers beleuchtet und strukturiert behandelt. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Vor allem die Übersicht „der häufigsten Fehler bei der Eröffnung eines Onlineshops“ sollte vor der Liveschaltung des Internet Verkaufskanals auf Versäumnisse überprüft werden. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Dazu gehören die Punkte wie 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;ul&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Das Impressum&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Die AGB und deren korrekte Einbindung in den Verkaufsprozess &lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Angaben über Lieferzeit&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Das Wiederrufsrecht, welches in der Schweiz einfacher ist als z.Bsp. Deutschland&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Die Datenschutzerklärung&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Transparente Preisangaben und Versandkosten&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Das Double Opt-In Verfahren für Newsletter und andere Kundenbindungs Aktivitäten&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Das Beachten von Urheberrechte von Dritten&lt;/li&gt; 
      &lt;/ul&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Erschwerend kommt hinzu, dass das Schweizer Recht nur innerhalb der Schweiz zum Einsatz kommt und zum Beispiel im EU Raum strengere Verbraucherschutz Richtlinien gelten. Diese sind zu beachten, falls man die Ware auch im EU Raum anbieten will. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Bei der sauberen Umsetzung der rechtlichen Bestimmungen wird gegenüber dem Kunden die notwendige Transparenz und Seriosität sichergestellt, welche schlussendlich Vertrauen auf Kundenseite gegenüber dem Unternehmen schafft.&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Man merke: Vertrauen ist die Grundlage jeder Geschäftsbeziehung zwischen dem Endkunden und Anbieter. Ohne Vertrauen kein Verkauf ! 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;u&gt;&lt;b&gt;Weiterführende Links&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;u&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/u&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;ul&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.steigerlegal.ch/2012/04/01/impressumspflicht-im-e-commerce-fragen-und-antworten/"&gt;Impressumspflicht im E-Commerce: Fragen und Antworten&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.conviva-plus.ch/index.php?page=1135"&gt;Muster Impressum Schweiz für Website CH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
      &lt;/ul&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Micro Business Quick Tips #2: Build a Business Without Employees</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/09/03/micro-business-quick-tips-2-build-a-business-without-employees.html"/>
    <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/09/03/micro-business-quick-tips-2-build-a-business-without-employees.html</id>
    <published>2015-09-03T05:41:56Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-30T06:46:35+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
        A helpful article by 
       &lt;a href="http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/249868"&gt;enterpreneur.com&lt;/a&gt; which outlines some basics of How to build a Seven-Figure Business Without Employees. As the article states 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;i&gt;The good news is that my lack of interest in such pursuits (… being famous and glamorous …)  hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a hindrance in building a seven figure-business, in a rather short period of time, with a single co-founder and no employees &amp;ndash; which can be operated from anywhere in the world with an Internet connection. As a matter of fact, I’m typing this at a cafe in Copenhagen, Denmark, and will be meandering through Europe for at least the next five weeks &amp;ndash; yet sales will continue to grow and the business won&amp;rsquo;t miss a step. I&amp;rsquo;m not bragging, just validating.&lt;/i&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        The replicable model comes with three simple key points 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;ul&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Start Simple: As for example &amp;ldquo;&lt;i&gt;you should avoid, at least at the beginning, from overcomplicating your sales pipeline with wholesale or retail scenarios and instead focus on taking your product direct to the consumer.&lt;/i&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Automate Early: Front to back from sales channel up to the inbound-support requests.&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Leverage Outsourcing: Here the statement is quite bold &lt;i&gt;&amp;ldquo;I’ve even written a few, but here we’re focusing on building a business that doesn’t require employees &amp;ndash; so we’re going to outsource it all.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt; 
      &lt;/ul&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Three points which we consider at Cloudburo.com as well when building up our first subscription based product centered around content marketing. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        The 
       &lt;a href="https://cloudburo.net/docs/products.html"&gt;Cloudburo Curation Platform&lt;/a&gt; will help you to establish your content online presence via a highly optimized and easy workflow to support you in establishing a web presence of the various content types. 
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.entrepreneur.com/article/249868"&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Docker Small Hints #6: Using Cloudwatch in combination with Log Entries Management Solution</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/08/11/docker-small-hints-6-using-cloudwatch-in-combination-with-log-entries-management.html"/>
    <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/08/11/docker-small-hints-6-using-cloudwatch-in-combination-with-log-entries-management.html</id>
    <published>2015-08-11T09:53:31Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-09T23:02:17+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
        As explained in my last article &amp;ldquo; 
       &lt;a href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/07/28/docker-small-hints-5-using-cloudwatch-alarms-for-monitoring-aws-elastic-beanstal.html"&gt;Using Cloudwatch Alarms for monitoring AWS Elastic Beanstalk Docker Instances&lt;/a&gt;“ I set up a Cloudwatch Alarm to detect inactivity/potential hanging scenarios of my micro service. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        In this article I will drill down and give  you some ideas how to configure your 
       &lt;a href="http://logentries.com/"&gt;logentries&lt;/a&gt; engine. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        As one can see in the following example the Cloudwatch Alarm was sending out an Alarm at 11:20 about inactivity of the microservice, which was released 5 minutes later again.&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/0ddb572232295e371a5ff2b5145ac5e2.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        So it seems that this was a false alarm. For the root cause analysis I normally check first then my logentries management instance. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        One powerful feature of logentries is to define any kind of tag  for a text pattern in your log event stream. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        For my microservice I defined amongst others the following tags 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;ul&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;„Gen“ which is attached to log events which contains the text „html.slim“. The microservice produces this log entry when a new article is added to the blog and the &lt;a href="https://middlemanapp.com/"&gt;middleman&lt;/a&gt; regeneration will take place&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;„Stats“ which is attached to log events which are providing processing time statistics for a blog checking and generation cycle. They contain the text „STAT.FullRoundtripTime“&lt;/li&gt; 
      &lt;/ul&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/281b875f295a1eef409c65d55fd2f5a0.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        The screenshot below shows me immediately that there was an inactivity phase starting around 11:10 which was terminated around 11:20. The logentries management solution didn’t get any event from my micro-service and therefore the Cloudwatch kicked off. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        By selecting the „Stats“ filter I  can conclude that the roundtrip time for the blog dognews was around 15 minutes, which was the reason for the Cloudwatch alarm. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        If you look at the graph you can see that the inactivity period is happening after a &amp;ldquo;light blue“ log event, which is the color of the „Gen“ tagged log entries. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/e4bb9fa15be75b695c4f7ead6295c9c9.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Filtering now for the „Gen“ log events, shows me immdeiately the root cause, i.e. the middleman generation cycle when a new entry is added lasts for 15 minutes for the dedicated blog „dognews“. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/ac488945374cb1a8d2e31b213144a7e7.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Taken into consideration that the blog is the largest one currently managed by the Cloudburo Curation Platform with over 300 articles the reason is clear: Middleman is regenerating the static website after each new article and this takes now considerable time (i.e. processing categories pages etc.). It also means I have to exploit possibilities to parallelize this processing area before going live. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        This concludes the article which  gives you some hints how to use the logentries management solution in combination with tags in order to get a quick overview about the state of your microservice. Carefully tagging your logentries allows you to get an overview of the health and status of your application in a very short period of time. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        This blog is managed fully out of Evernote by using the Cloudburo Curation Platform. Interested - head over to &lt;a href="https://cloudburo.net/docs/products.html"&gt;https://cloudburo.net/docs/products.html&lt;/a&gt;. 
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Docker Small Hints #5: Using Cloudwatch Alarms for monitoring AWS Elastic Beanstalk Docker Instances</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/07/28/docker-small-hints-5-using-cloudwatch-alarms-for-monitoring-aws-elastic-beanstal.html"/>
    <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/07/28/docker-small-hints-5-using-cloudwatch-alarms-for-monitoring-aws-elastic-beanstal.html</id>
    <published>2015-07-28T10:16:46Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-09T23:02:17+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
        My first docker based 
       &lt;a href="https://curation.cloudburo.net/"&gt;content curation microservice&lt;/a&gt; is in early beta mode and is working reliably for a longer period of time now. The last deployment of the application was up and running for 46 days without any major operational incident. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Suddenly the Micro-service stopped to generate blog entries out of Evernote Notes. I wasn’t monitoring this constellation up until now and detected it just about 4 hours later. Not very good when you want to go live. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        So time to start monitoring such kind of incidents by using  CloudWatch and start sending out alarm emails in order to be capable to keep the service live all the time. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Elastic Beanstalk automatically uses&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;a href="http://docs.aws.amazon.com/elasticbeanstalk/latest/dg/AWSHowTo.cloudwatch.html"&gt;Amazon CloudWatch&lt;/a&gt; to help you  monitor your application and environment status.  The Amazon CloudWatch console gives you an overview of all of your resources as well as your alarms.&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/c4254846da654fcf8f562b647a640a54.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        In order to handle this new kind of incidents it’s necessary to create a new alarm which detects the pattern, but &amp;hellip; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        … first the root cause analysis must be done, what the heck stopped to work as expected. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        My primary monitoring application for the java based micro service is 
       &lt;a href="https://logentries.com/"&gt;logentries.com&lt;/a&gt;. The java/groovy application on the EB Docker instance will send various kind of log information (via log4j  to the logentries log management and analytics application). 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        As one can see in the below 24 hours log, everthing seems find up around 10:00 where no micro service log entries were shown anymore. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/ad9e91d21c0ec36e7aa2f399178f089a.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        That means something stopped working on the Amazon Docker instance, which wasn’t detected by AWS EB manager itself. E.g. in case my Microservice App would memory leaked over time and crash at one time, the AWS EB manager would detect that an restart the microservice automatically  (making the application available again after some minutes). Such an incident wouldn’t result in the above pattern. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        So I had to go on and check the AWS EB Docker instance logs directly (refer to the 
       &lt;a href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/04/25/docker-small-hints-3-ssh-into-your-aws-elastic-beanstalk-component.html"&gt;following article&lt;/a&gt; how to achieve that).  A first glance  showed me that the java based microservice application was still running (on top of the list, consuming the major part of the memory). No restart or anything else happened, uptime was 46 days. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/71b4a9fbe17004641f16073d2c17628a.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        So let’s check then the application log of the eb docker container, which can be found in the /var/log/… directory. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/5dc5c78335f67a3340f824951697f0e4.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Counter checking with the last message received by logentries, it lead to the conclusion, that the local log is in sync with the logentries remote one. So the java process stopped working at that point in time and wasn’t producing any log events anymore. So we have to establish a monitoring strategy which is capable of identifying our hanging micro service process. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Time to define an AWS Cloudwatch Alert which will allows me to detect this inactivity/hanging process behavior. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Looking at the EB Monitoring in the Dashboard shows me that such an incident would result in &amp;ldquo;Max Network In“ flow of a small amount of KB’s (refer to the 
       &lt;a href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/04/09/docker-small-hints-1-high-level-concepts-elastic-beanstalk.html"&gt;following article&lt;/a&gt; to understand the high level EB concepts). This seems to be the strongest signal for such a behaviour. Using the low CPU Utilization as a signal, seems not advisable, due to the fact that this threshold could shift in case of auto scaling scenarios. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/8bd6de153b5e793c550b2185ba7f8d94.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Just to be sure I checked  the graph over a two weeks period of time. It shows me that this seems a good signal for a hanging microservice java process. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/813200dfe04e9b01b5d13837ee10ca7f.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Now let’s create an Alarm then, which is straightforward and easy and can be done on the EB Monitoring site directly. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/0f96def25c50580998ff55218391d961.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Let’s go back to the Dashboard to see if the Alarm is, correctly shown. Yes it got triggered. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/e63d6ee6edc3c73364addaae60b2cffb.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        The Alarm Dashboard shows the existing Alarm, very nice. It will be also visible on the Cloudwatch Dashboard site. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/4a88ab998c68e7eee4fbe76c2c0a418d.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        I also get notified via Email by the AWS Notification service to subscribe for the topic.&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/513a3b55b0b3186a6c20103e82000aa9.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        Having done that I will now receive an email when my microservice is hanging or inactive for more than some minutes. It allows me to timely restart or investigate the problem which results in a better service level for my clients. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        In a next article I will investigate in the possibilities to automate the creation of CloudWatch Alarms during my EB Environment creation step. 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;img class="img-responsive img-thumbnail article" src="/images/3c1663d43864486db5b237ca1a1546e0.png" /&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Launching a New Product? These 5 Tips Will Get You the Testimonials You Need</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/07/26/launching-a-new-product-these-5-tips-will-get-you-the-testimonials-you-need.html"/>
    <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net/2015/07/26/launching-a-new-product-these-5-tips-will-get-you-the-testimonials-you-need.html</id>
    <published>2015-07-26T11:18:54Z</published>
    <updated>2015-09-30T05:39:13+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt;
         Demian Farnworth was publishing a very helpful article on the well known &amp;ldquo;copyblogger&amp;rdquo; site about the strategy how to get testimonials for your new product launch.&lt;br&gt;
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt; 
        &lt;br&gt; 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt;
         The article starts with a very illustrative thought experiment about the importance of trust 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt; 
        &lt;i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/i&gt; 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt; 
        &lt;i&gt;&amp;hellip; look at your birth certificate to confirm that you were indeed born on the day that your parents said you were born?&lt;/i&gt; 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt; 
        &lt;i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/i&gt; 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt; 
        &lt;i&gt;For most people, the answer is never. You simply took your parents’ word. Because you trusted them.&lt;/i&gt; 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt; 
        &lt;i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/i&gt; 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt; 
        &lt;i&gt;Your parents hopefully did a lot of things to help build that trust — like feed and clothe you, teach you lessons, play with you, and protect you. People who don’t have that experience, however, feel something entirely different: they question everything. They don’t inherently trust.&lt;/i&gt; 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt; 
        &lt;i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/i&gt; 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt; 
        &lt;i&gt;For most of us, though, if we read or hear something from someone we know, like, and trust, we accept it without question.&lt;/i&gt; 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt; 
        &lt;br&gt; 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt; 
        &lt;i&gt;As an entrepreneur, you need to think of your customer as a child who’s been burned one too many times. Who’s been hoodwinked, ridiculed, and neglected. Who’s defensive, reserved, and hard-nosed.&lt;/i&gt; 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt; 
        &lt;br&gt; 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt;
         The article moves on and introduces five simple methods to get hold of testimonials, which are seen as a prove of your claim about the usefullness of your new launched product: 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
       &lt;div&gt; 
        &lt;br&gt; 
       &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;ul&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Offer free trials&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Create superb welcome experiences&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Ask for volunteers&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Build relationships with credible experts&lt;/li&gt; 
       &lt;li&gt;Invite people to a beta version&lt;/li&gt; 
      &lt;/ul&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div&gt;
        You can find the full article here 
      &lt;/div&gt; 
      &lt;div style=""&gt; 
       &lt;br&gt; 
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.copyblogger.com/get-testimonials/"&gt;Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
