<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>dev@cloudburo</title>
  <subtitle></subtitle>
  <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net</id>
  <link href="https://dev.cloudburo.net"/>
  <link href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <updated>2016-12-01T22:20:29Z</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Felix K?stahler</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>The Human Being(s) and We (as a Bank) #1 - Relationship</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2016/12/01/the-human-being-s-and-we-as-a-bank-1-relationship.html"/>
    <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net/2016/12/01/the-human-being-s-and-we-as-a-bank-1-relationship.html</id>
    <published>2016-12-01T22:20:29Z</published>
    <updated>2016-12-01T23:03:27+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
        Under this title I will publish articles how established banks should approach their customers in a digital world with a client centric view in mind. I will concentrate here on the view which is generally managed in a bank by a 
       &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Customer_relationship_management"&gt;Customer Relationship Management&lt;/a&gt; (CRM) system. Obviously there are other views which are important for a bank, i.e. a client risk exposure- or client profitability view, but all these  others view are out of scope here.&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        First of all, a bank is interacting with Persons and nothing more. An Person is a human being who has an real identity (and often multiple digital identities), who got born somewhere on this planet, may have a nationality and is domiciled in a country at a certain point in time.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        As a side remark, this is the normal case unfortunately there a stateless persons which may have no domicile at the moment, which were treated as unbanked persons,
       &lt;a href="http://www.worldbank.org/en/programs/globalfindex"&gt;as another 2.5 billions persons mainly in poor countries&lt;/a&gt;. A topic for another article, which will show the opportunities for digital banks who starting serving this segment. 
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        For sure the bank will make businesses with a company or a family office, but finally the bank is  interacting with an individual (or a group of individuals) which may representing in a certain
       &lt;u&gt;role &lt;/u&gt;a company, a simple partnership, a trust or family office. 
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;This is the first important recognition&lt;/b&gt;: Persons are the centre of interests which are interacting with us in one or multiple roles. We cannot interact directly with a company or group construct we are always in contact with human beings.&lt;/i&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        I explicitly don’t use the term “customer” here. We as a bank (you could generalize it to any other industry) will have Person relationships which we may be aware of or not and which may finally result in a customer relationship, which results in some profits for us.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The second important recognition&lt;/b&gt;: It’s about relationships, being in no relationship with a Person, means he (as well as we) are not aware of each other (non-existent for the moment) and not reachable for any kind of business.&lt;/i&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        This leads us to the concept of relationship phases, which are used to position persons which are interacting with us.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        The four Relationship Phases are sequenced one after the other, but a Person may switch from one to another in a non-sequenced way and may visit a phase multiple times during his life time. 
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        Relationship means mutual interaction and may require certain obligations and rules on both sides.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        So let’s look at the four relationship phases, a Person may be in an &amp;hellip;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;b&gt;(1) … Information Relationship&lt;/b&gt; with us when browsing our web pages, reading our printed brochues, listening to our podcasts or watching our ads. He is not
       &lt;u&gt;explicitly&lt;/u&gt; willing to share any personal information with us, but implicitly may accept (or not, by taking additional measures, i.e. anonymous browsing) that we are tracking him in context of a digital information relationship (e.g. tracking his activities on our sites with cookies as a nameless human being)
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Obligation on Person&lt;/i&gt;: none&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Obligation on Us&lt;/i&gt;: Jurisdictional Cookie Rules (e.g. &lt;a href="http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/DE/ALL/?uri=CELEX:32009L0136"&gt;EU&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.admin.ch/opc/de/classified-compilation/19970160/index.html#a45c"&gt;CH&lt;/a&gt;) compliancy, expressed in a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Privacy_policy"&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/a&gt; (which may vary per jurisdiction due to the differences of the applicable law)&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;b&gt;(2) … Trust Relationship &lt;/b&gt;with us when leaving us some personal information, so that we can get in contact with him (e.g. an Email). Depending on his trust level in us, he is willing to provide additional information about him, so that we can better understand him as an individual as well his current or future needs. By doing that he allows us to move him out of our nameless individual based pool of public aggregated data that covers only a slice of its existence into a contactable person.&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Obligation on Person: &lt;/i&gt;none&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Obligation on Us: &lt;/i&gt; The obligations of (1) and an enhanced Privacy Policy (covering the handling of the personal data collected) in line with the Data Protection Act of our jurisdiction (refer to the &lt;a href="https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-data-protection/key-definitions/"&gt;UK ICO definition&lt;/a&gt; of the DPA term). A DPA could also include the “&lt;a href="http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/files/factsheets/factsheet_data_protection_en.pdf"&gt;Right to be Forgotten&lt;/a&gt;”, which would switch a person back into Phase (1) when executed (we wouldn’t know him anymore, because he lost trust in us). &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;b&gt;(3) … Business Relationship &lt;/b&gt;with us, when purchasing certain products and services which we can offer outside of the legal framework of a bank. This may be a personalised research report, or a real time quotes notification for our public internet quotes system, for which the client is willing to pay some one-off or subscription fees. These are any kind of products for which non-banking rules and regulation applies. As an example we may sell a promotional branding teddy bear via our online shop in order to attract the young generation of the retail segment. In this case we have to ensure that our product complies with the jurisdictional laws about kids toy.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Obligation on Person: &lt;/i&gt; The obligation laid out in our Sales &lt;a href="http://www.businessdictionary.com/definition/agreement.html"&gt;Agreement&lt;/a&gt; for the product/service in the role of a Buyer. Our Sales agreement is backed normally by  &lt;a href="http://www.businessdictionary.com/definition/agreement.html"&gt;Terms of Conditions (TOC)&lt;/a&gt; (or Terms of Services).&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Obligation on Us: &lt;/i&gt; The obligation of (1)+(2) and potentially an enhanced Privacy Policy (in case we share the data with a third party for credit card payments or physical package delivery etc.), plus our Sales Agreement and Terms of Conditions in the role of the Seller.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;/ul&gt;
       &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
       &lt;/div&gt;
       &lt;b&gt;(4) … Banking Relationship &lt;/b&gt;with us, when purchasing banking products/services from us. These offerings require that we have a
       &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Banking_license"&gt;Banking Licence&lt;/a&gt; in the jurisdiction where our bank is incorporated.  The legal and regulatory obligation on us in context of knowing our person (
       &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Know_your_customer"&gt;KYC&lt;/a&gt;) will rise here exponentially. But that’s the phase which we want ultimately achieve with a person relationship, i.e. the person (well it’s now a customer) highly trusts in us and transfer money to us, which we manage on keep on his behalf. He may be even see us as a trusted advisor for any kind  of investment decision. 
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Obligation on Person&lt;/i&gt;: Correctly answer any kind question required by the KYC check, provisioning of valid identity card. The obligation as a banking service consumer laid out in our Banking Relationship Agreement  and TOC. For each purchased Banking Product/Service the corresponding Product/Service Agreement  and TOC in the role of a buyer.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;Obligation on Us:&lt;/i&gt; The obligation of (1)+(2) and a enhanced Privacy Policy which may include specific &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bank_secrecy"&gt;Banking Secrecy&lt;/a&gt; Rules of the jurisdiction where we are incorporated. The obligation to identify and verify the identity of our customer in line with the jurisdictional KYC rule. The obligation as a banking service provider laid out in our Banking Relationship Agreement  and TOC. For each purchased Banking Product/Service the corresponding Product/Service Agreement  and TOC in the role of a seller.&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Third and final recognition for today&lt;/b&gt;: Four Relationship Phases are enough to position a Person interacting with us as a Bank. Each phase will move the Person closer to our goal to win him as customer. This user journey along the four phases is based &lt;u&gt;on an increase of&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;… Trust in us: Which is indispensable and which we have to gain every day&lt;br&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;… Obligation on us: To handle his data diligently and in line with any kind of regulation. Not doing it will result over time in a loss of trust in us which may result not achieving our goal&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;… Knowledge about him&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;i&gt; Having trust in us, a Person will be willing to share more information about him, which will strengthen our position as a trusted advisor.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;i&gt;… Identity Accuracy of him&lt;/i&gt;: The more information we have about him, the higher accuracy about his real identity we achieve. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;/ul&gt;
       &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
       &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        That’s it for today: Did you realize there is no sales funnel yet, a topic for the next article.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        Finally Thinking Out of the Box: Edge Perspectives by John Hagel about
       &lt;a href="http://edgeperspectives.typepad.com/edge_perspectives/2015/03/disruption-by-trusted-advisors.html"&gt;Disruption by the Trusted Advisor&lt;/a&gt;, stretches the topic even more. Do we as a Bank can act in the future as a trusted advisor for our  clients by just offering our products and services - well not really ?&lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;i&gt;This blog entry was fully produced within Evernote and published using the &lt;a href="https://publishingbot.cloudburo.net"&gt;Cloudburo Publishing Bot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blockchain Smart Signatures Explained</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2016/11/30/blockchain-smart-signatures-explained.html"/>
    <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net/2016/11/30/blockchain-smart-signatures-explained.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-30T22:56:42Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-30T22:56:42+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
        Christopher Allen provides all the time very profound blog articles in the context of blockchain, identity and authorization topics.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        The Smart Signatures white paper from Rebooting the Web of Trust conference is giving an excellent and easy to understand introduction to the topic of Smart Signatures.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        Out of the abstract of the paper, Smart Signatures are defined as follows.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;i&gt;Traditional cryptographic signature systems are based on &lt;b&gt;strictly-defined &lt;/b&gt;authentication and authorization mechanisms that &lt;b&gt;assume a single private key&lt;/b&gt; can be used to produce a given signature and that a single public key can be used to verify it. Given the evident limitations of this design, we propose an alternative with more powerful capabilties, based on the ability to &lt;b&gt;explicitly outline&lt;/b&gt; and fully &lt;b&gt;program conditions for verification&lt;/b&gt;. These conditions would then be used to determine when a signature or set of signatures can be considered valid.&lt;/i&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        This requirement of explicitly define authorization rules for the (multiple) signature(s) check is a core principle of the blockchain aka bitcoin, and an invention which enhancing authorisation strategies dramatically.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        The authors will describe the topic of Smart Signatures in context of the Bitcoin Script language and provides various use cases and implementation statuses.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        You can find the white paper
       &lt;a href="https://github.com/WebOfTrustInfo/rebooting-the-web-of-trust/blob/master/final-documents/smart-signatures.pdf"&gt;&lt;b&gt;here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;i&gt;This blog entry was fully produced within Evernote and published using the &lt;a href="https://publishingbot.cloudburo.net"&gt;Cloudburo Publishing Bot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The 5 pillars of the AWS Architecture Framework</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2016/11/29/the-5-pillars-of-the-aws-architecture-framework.html"/>
    <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net/2016/11/29/the-5-pillars-of-the-aws-architecture-framework.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-29T21:48:26Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-29T21:48:26+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
        Recently I published an article about the
       &lt;a href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2016/11/28/the-twelve-factor-app-methodology-for-building-saas.html"&gt;Twelve Factor App Methodology for SAAS&lt;/a&gt;, which can be applied for any programming language.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        In case you decide to go with
       &lt;a href="http://aws.amazon.com"&gt;aws.amazon.com&lt;/a&gt; you can complement the methodology with
       &lt;a href="http://d0.awsstatic.com/whitepapers/architecture/AWS_Well-Architected_Framework.pdf"&gt;AWS Architecture Framework&lt;/a&gt;, which provides you with a solid architectural foundation for building these new kind of applications. The white paper got recently updated (November 2016) an addresses general design principles, as well as specific best practices and guidance in five conceptual areas that AWS defines as the pillars of the Well-Architected Framework.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;ol&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Security&lt;/b&gt;: The ability to protect information, systems, and assets while delivering business value through risk assessments and mitigation strategies.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reliability&lt;/b&gt;:  The ability of a system to recover from infrastructure or service failures, dynamically acquire computing resources to meet demand, and mitigate disruptions such as misconfigurations or transient network issues.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Performance Efficiency: &lt;/b&gt;The ability to use computing resources efficiently to meet system requirements, and to maintain that efficiency as demand changes and technologies evolve.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cost Optimization&lt;/b&gt;: The ability to avoid or eliminate unneeded cost or suboptimal resources.   &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Operational Excellence: &lt;/b&gt;The ability to run and monitor systems to deliver business value and to continually improve supporting processes and procedures.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        When architecting solutions you make trade-offs between pillars based upon your business context, these business decisions can drive your engineering priorities. 
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        The paper will help you to make the right decisions in context of application requirements and is a guiding light in the sometimes complex AWS ecosystems
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        You can find the full white paper:
       &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://d0.awsstatic.com/whitepapers/architecture/AWS_Well-Architected_Framework.pdf"&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        My articles to the usage of the Amazon cloud you will find under the tag
       &lt;a href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/tags/aws.html"&gt;aws&lt;/a&gt;.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;b&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;i&gt;This blog entry was fully produced within Evernote and published using the &lt;a href="https://publishingbot.cloudburo.net"&gt;Cloudburo Publishing Bot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Twelve Factor App Methodology for Building SAAS</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2016/11/28/the-twelve-factor-app-methodology-for-building-saas.html"/>
    <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net/2016/11/28/the-twelve-factor-app-methodology-for-building-saas.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-28T21:33:21Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-28T21:39:12+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
        Deliver applications as “Software-As-A-Service” in a Cloud Platform requires to take some principles into consideration, which were not immediately obvious when coming from a classic development environment.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        The
       &lt;a href="http://12factor.net"&gt;12factor.net&lt;/a&gt; Web page provides the so-called twelve-factor app methodology for building software-as-a-service apps. It can be applied to apps written in any language and using any combination of backing service.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        It’s centred around the core principles of
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Use &lt;b&gt;declarative&lt;/b&gt; formats for setup automation, to minimize time and cost for new developers joining the project;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Have a &lt;b&gt;clean contrac&lt;/b&gt;t with the underlying operating system, offering maximum portability between execution environments;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Are suitable for &lt;b&gt;deployment&lt;/b&gt; on modern cloud platforms, obviating the need for servers and systems administration;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Minimize divergence&lt;/b&gt; between development and production, enabling continuous deployment for maximum agility;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;And can &lt;b&gt;scale up&lt;/b&gt; without significant changes to tooling, architecture, or development practices.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;Use it as your guiding cookbook when starting newly with writing software-as-a-service apps.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;a href="http://12factor.net"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Check it out here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;i&gt;This blog entry was fully produced within Evernote and published using the &lt;a href="https://publishingbot.cloudburo.net"&gt;Cloudburo Publishing Bot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Blockchain Governance System Introduction</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2016/11/22/blockchain-governance-system-introduction.html"/>
    <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net/2016/11/22/blockchain-governance-system-introduction.html</id>
    <published>2016-11-22T22:15:39Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-27T21:51:45+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
        Josh Stark provides in
       &lt;a href="http://www.coindesk.com/making-sense-blockchain-governance-applications/"&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; an excellent introduction to the topic of Blockchain Governance Applications.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        It starts with a simple definition of the term “Governance”
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;i&gt;This is what I mean by &amp;ldquo;governance&amp;rdquo; for the purposes of this article – the processes and systems used to facilitate decision-making in any organization.&lt;/i&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        This decision making process requires some basic technologies, which are provided in this context by the blockchain technology.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        Amongst others these are
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;First, it requires a way to record a set of rules. Rules like who gets to vote, who gets to sit in parliament or who has commit access to a codebase.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Second, there must be a way for people to interact with the rules.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Third, governance systems require a way to enforce the rules.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;The article introduces a simple example of a voting system used by an NGO and then applies the blockchain technology to provide a Governance Application solution to the use case. This illustration process is very helpful in getting a quick and easy to understand overview of this rather complex domain.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        The benefits of the blockchain in the above example are
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;First, blockchains are ideal for recording information in a way that can be later verified as authoritative. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Second, blockchains provide a new way for people to interact with the rules directly. Some blockchains allow users to create logical scripts that are executed by the blockchain itself (smart contract code), which are executing the agreed rule.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;Having the rule express as executable code in the blockchain itself we have already achieved our third requirement – enforcement. When the rule is expressed as executable code, the rule can be enforced at the same time it is exercised.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
       &lt;/ul&gt;
       &lt;div&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
       &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        These three blockchain features are the foundation of any bitcoin governance system.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
        The author then goes on a introduces the bigger picture as well outlines various existing use cases. You can find the full article
       &lt;a href="http://www.coindesk.com/making-sense-blockchain-governance-applications/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;i&gt;This blog entry was fully produced within Evernote and published using the &lt;a href="https://publishingbot.cloudburo.net"&gt;Cloudburo Publishing Bot&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div&gt;
       &lt;br&gt;
      &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Meteor Small Hints #5: Server Code Fragments executed twice on Startup</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://dev.cloudburo.net/2016/07/18/meteor-small-hints-5-server-code-fragments-executed-twice-on-startup.html"/>
    <id>https://dev.cloudburo.net/2016/07/18/meteor-small-hints-5-server-code-fragments-executed-twice-on-startup.html</id>
    <published>2016-07-18T16:06:09Z</published>
    <updated>2016-11-27T21:51:45+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Article Author</name>
    </author>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="row"&gt;
  &lt;div class="article"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span/&gt;      &lt;div&gt;
    Recently I got confused with my Meteor application, by having the server code executed twice at startup. So the code was initialising my application twice, as well as duplicated for example my Slack Sysadmin Bot running as part of the instance.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    I was first thinking that it has something to do with my IntelliJ Webstorm IDE running in debug mode, but also the local test-, as well the my Modulus remote environment was showing the same symptom.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    After some hours of debugging I luckily found the following
   &lt;a href="https://github.com/Differential/meteor-workers/issues/9"&gt;Github issue entry&lt;/a&gt; which showed me the right direction.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    As part of my application I introduced
   &lt;a href="https://github.com/Differential/meteor-workers"&gt;Differential meteor-workers&lt;/a&gt;, which allows to spawn headless worker meteor processes to work on async jobs. For example, passing a message to my Slack SysAdmin Bot is done via Job.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight coffeescript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;class&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="vi"&gt;@&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;SlackSysAdminBotJob&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;extends&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;Job&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class="na"&gt;handleJob&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="vi"&gt;@&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;action&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;==&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;"sendMessage"&lt;/span&gt; 
        &lt;span class="vi"&gt;@&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;bot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;postTo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="vi"&gt;@&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="vi"&gt;@&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;text&lt;/span&gt; 

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
    Such a async Job can be easily triggered, like shown here (which will hand the work over to a worker process.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight coffeescript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;
    &lt;span class="nx"&gt;Job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;push&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="k"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;SlackSysAdminBotJob&lt;/span&gt; 
          &lt;span class="na"&gt;action&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;"sendMessage"&lt;/span&gt; 
          &lt;span class="na"&gt;slackBot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;myBot&lt;/span&gt; 
          &lt;span class="na"&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;txt&lt;/span&gt; 
          &lt;span class="na"&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;channel&lt;/span&gt; 
        &lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;error&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;job&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
           &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Check it 
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
    Now introducing the Differential async worker resulted in the problem, that not only the master process, BUT also the worker process will be initialised with each Server startup code fragment. Which is not what we want.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    So I had to extend each server Meter.startup code fragment by introducing an
   &lt;i&gt;isClusterMaster&lt;/i&gt; check
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight coffeescript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  &lt;span class="nx"&gt;exports&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;Plattform&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span class="na"&gt;isClusterMaster&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;Meteor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;isServer&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;amp;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;Npm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;require&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;'cluster'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;isMaster&lt;/span&gt; 


&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
    As for example:
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class="highlight coffeescript"&gt;&lt;code&gt;
  &lt;span class="nx"&gt;Meteor&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;startup&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;Plattform&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;isClusterMaster&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; 
      &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# The startup code 
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Now the startup initialization will be only executed on the master in the cluster and not for each worker process.
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
   &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
